# **David Mulholland**

Full-stack JavaScript developer specialising in React, Redux, Node, Express and MongoDB.

Portfolio: <a href="https://webdev-davidm.github.io/Portfolio/">https://webdev-davidm.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-mulholland-07b86319a/

Github: <a href="https://github.com/Webdev-DavidM">https://github.com/Webdev-DavidM</a>

## Mobile: 07790145535

E-mail::davidm.webdeveloper@gmai

l.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Following a successful career for 10 years in the housing industry, I decided on a career change to become a web developer. I have been studying full time for a year and have gained certificates as a front-end web developer, react developer and as a full-stack JavaScript developer. I have also created projects from the freecodecamp curriculum, Javascript 30 and numerous Udemy courses, all of which have solidified my skills and can be viewed on my github account.

During my treehouse study I developed team working skills by assisting others with technical issues on slack and using git for version control and submitting projects. As I became more experienced I conducted code reviews on other's student's projects.

Having completed these courses, I now aspire to be a developer more than ever. I enjoy combining technical and creative skills, learning new technology and solving problems. I get real satisfaction working with others on projects. Equally I am self-motivated and as my portfolio shows, I can produce complex full-stack applications on my own when required.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages:

**JavaScript** 

Front-end:

HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JQuery, React, React native, Redux

Back-end:

Express, Jade, Node, Mongo DB, Mongoose ORM, mySql

Other:

Git version control, Heroku, Visual studio code, Webpack

#### **NOTABLE PROJECTS**

## Object-oriented game show project

https://webdev-davidm.github.io/THFS-OOP-game-show/

This project consists of three main objects called game, app and phrase. These objects and their methods interact to create the game.

#### React book reading app

https://webdev-davidm.github.io/udacity-react-myreads/

This react app shows all the keys parts of managing state using react class-based components. There is also a search function to add books.

#### **EDUCATION**

## React Nanodegree, Udacity,

September 2020-October 2020

## Full-stack JavaScript Tech degree, Treehouse

March 2020-August 2020

#### Front-end Tech degree, Treehouse

October 2019- March 2020

## Youtube React video player

https://webdev-davidm.github.io/React-hooks-youtube-gallery/

I created this app which uses react hooks to access the youtube api and display my favourite youtube videos in a modal window.

#### Statistical dashboard

https://webdev-davidm.github.io/TDFE-project7-web-app-dashboard/

This project I created uses css grid,flexbox, chart.js, jquery and local storage to create a company dashboard

### Full stack student courses app

https://webdev-davidm.github.io/thfs-final-project-react-front-end/

In this project I created a backend api using express and mongoDB and a front end react application to connect to it. The backend authenticates users using bcrypt and validates data submitted by the user. The front end is made with react and uses the context api to provide user authentication throughout the application. Click on the link for more details about the

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Housing specialist team, Clarion housing group

March 2018- October 2019

Housing customer account officer, Clarion housing group

February 2016- March 2018

Landlord licensing scheme officer-secondment, Croydon council

June 2015-February 2016

Housing advisor, Croydon council

June 2012-June 2015

## CCNA & Network+ certification, Comptia

Circa 2001

**2:1 BA Hons, Media production,** Humberside university

1996-1999